Janesh T

9884343703 • joshuajanesh12@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/janesh-t-5a0854142

Objective

My main goal as Onboarding Specialist is to contribute to the company's success by implementing solid and highly productive end to end recruitment processes. Along with the cooperation of competent intra- and interorganizational networks, I am positive that this goal can be achieved. One of my objectives is continuous professional enhancement as an Onboarding Specialist and be among the best in my field of expense. With this said, I am confident that I will be an asset to the company.

Experience

JULY 2023- PRESENT

Onboarding Specialist / GUVI Geek Networks / Chennai

Roles and Responsibilities

- > Sourcing authors based on the requirement from the company through relevant hiring platforms.
- Preparing course communication with the appropriate Manager.
- > Delegating tasks to the new authors and answering their quires.
- Preparing cold calling list on author based on technology when required.
- > Supporting the authors till completion of course and following up with them till they finish the course and communicate them regarding rework planned if any.
- Preparing onboarding emails and documents for the author to start the process.
- > Staying up to date with innovative and creative ways of Onboarding new geeks.

JUNE 2021 – NOVEMBER 2022

Junior Executive -TAG / Cognizant Technology Solution / Chennai

Handing Two Client Accounts -AMEX and ANZ Recruiting Candidates for IT Skills 4+Years Experience Handling End to End Recruitment

Roles and Responsibilities

- > Sourcing-Source the candidates from the job portal like LinkedIn, Naukri and Monster and find the right candidate for the right job opportunity. Screening to know the candidates interest level against job requirements.
- > Screening-Post Screening will determine whether the candidate is qualified for the job role based on their education, experience and information based on their resume and to decide whether to proceed for next level of hiring or to reject the application.
- Scheduling-Setting up the Interview between the panel and the candidate by checking their availability with the most convenient times.

- > **Selecting**-Process of hiring employees among the shortlisted candidates with an effective recruitment and selection policy and providing them in organization.
- > **Documentation**-Recording employment information such as BGV (Back Ground Verification checks, Validate the document, resume, job description, offer letter, recruitment tracker, Candidate Information Sheet (CIS), relieving letter etc.
- Offer Release-Candidates will be issued an offer letter, which will describe the designation date of joining, job location roles and responsibilities, remunerations, benefits and terms and conditions related to company policies.
- On boarding-Welcoming new candidates and sending joining formalizes, induction program and training details.

MARCH 2020 - NOVEMBER 2020

Assistant Manager / ICICI Bank LTD / Chennai

Roles and Responsibilities

- Maintain a Relationship with the customer related to bank accounts and banking services.
- Cross selling the banking products to customers like FD, RD, Insurance (AII), SIP, mutual funds.
- Handling customer queries.

Skills

Staffing/Sourcing / End to End Recruitment / Recruitment and Talent Acquisition Group / Vendor Management / Onboarding and Training / Compliance / Human Resources Analytics / Employee Relationship / Performance Management / Compensation and Benefits / Conflict Resolution / Strategic Planning / Communication / Networking Connection / Time Management / Interpersonal / Decision Making / Multi-Tasking / Documents Processing

Education

JULY 2017 - APRIL 2019

DG VAISHNAV COLLEGE

MBA (FINANCE & MARKETING)

AUGUST 2014 - MAY 2017

DR.MGR UNIVERSITY

B.COM (GENERAL)

Projects / Internship

- A Study about consumers satisfaction on middle segment cars -Maruti Suzuki Arena-Marketing Department (Nov 2018-Jan 2019) (Project)
- > TVS Sundaram Clayton Pvt Ltd -Marketing Department (May 2018) (Internship)
- > Tamil Nadu State Co-Operative Bank Ltd Finance Department (December 2017) (Internship)

Certificates

- > Excel with LinkedIn Recruiter Access- LinkedIn
- > Human resources Concept Certificate- Udemy
- > Human Resources Analyst and Advanced Excel for Human Resources Management Certificate-Udemy
- > Chat GPT in Human Resources Management- Great Learning
- > Data Visualization with Power BI Great Learning